The court has already made its ruling.
这个法院已经判了啊
And I won the case.
胜诉的是我啊
The second thing is my recent experience with buying a car.
第二件事是我最近买车的各种各样的经历啊
It really made me realize how difficult it is to own a car in Beijing.
让我觉得真的是在北京拥有一辆车非常不容易
The third thing is closely related to all of you.
第三件事是跟大家息息相关的
If you have a special skill right now,
就是如果你现在有一技之长
If you want to make some money with Brother Rong,
想跟荣哥这儿赚点钱的话
we have a strategy.
咱们是有方法的啊
Let's start with the first topic.
然后咱们开始第一个话题
I won this case.
我这次胜诉了
The main reason for winning wasn't about being in the right.
这次胜诉的主要原因在于还不是理亏
It's not about who is in the wrong.
不理亏的问题
It's not a matter of who is at fault.
不是谁理亏的问题
Most importantly,
最重要来讲
I think it's because I entrusted Captain Bai, our lawyer.
我觉得是因为我委托了我们的舰长白律师啊
It's about having professionals handle professional matters.
这个专业的人干专业的事儿啊
When facing legal disputes
遇到法律纠纷
Any kind of legal conflicts
任何的司法纠纷
Reputation rights disputes
名誉权纠纷
Copyright disputes
著作权纠纷
Or even some criminal cases
还是一些刑事案件之类的
Make sure you do
一定一定啊
You must spend money to hire a good lawyer This point is crucial Because you didn't study law You might lack the necessary experience Never go to court to represent yourself.
一定要花钱请个好律师 这一点是非常重要的 因为你你专业不是学法律的啊 很多东西你可能经验啊完全不够 千万不要去法庭自诉啊
When it comes to many of your aspects,
你的很多东西来讲的话
they might seem very naive from the perspective of professional legal workers.
其实在人家专业的司法工作者眼里来讲
So, a lot of things shouldn't be handled this way.
看可能是非常幼稚的啊
Regarding the details of the case,
所以很多事呢不能这么干啊
I don't want to go into specifics.
关于案件的细节呢
Of course, I won the case.
我就不想具体透露了啊
The other party has to pay compensation,
当然来讲我赢了
and offer an apology.
对方又得赔钱
Got to give this apology again
又得这个道歉
This is the very core content.
这是这个很很很核心的内容啊
Of course, the other party also has the right to appeal.
当然来讲对方也有上诉的权利
By August 30th,
到8月30号
if he doesn’t appeal again,
他要不再上诉的话
the judgment will take effect.
这判决就生效了啊
Regarding this case,
其实关于这次这案子
I just want to make a few points.
我只想说几点
One is about cyber-bullying,
一个是呢网络暴力呢
which is something everyone detests.
这个东西呢是任何人都深恶痛绝的
Regardless of anything,
无论怎么样
No matter what your intentions are
你是出于任何的目的
exposing someone's private information online is wrong
你在网上曝光他人的隐私隐私
especially when it involves their family and financial status
特别是一些啊涉及别人家庭跟生活财产状况
or the education of their children
子女教育的情况
these matters
这些东西来讲
are inherently illegal
它本身就是违法的
don't do it just because the other person is nice for whatever reason no matter what you do if you feel that they are damaging your reputation You're spreading rumors or something? It's not about who shouts the loudest being right.
不要因为对方好 就是因为一个怎么说呢 无论你怎么样 你感觉到对方只要他在名誉权这方面给你造 你谣了或者怎么样了 不是说谁的嗓门大谁就有理啊
Firstly, the illegal act came first, let's talk about that.
首先是违法行为在前再说
He has also been the defendant in multiple similar defamation disputes.
他也是多起这个类似的名誉权纠纷的被告啊
It's become a habit for him to do such things.
就是习以为常的干这种事啊
As a cadre of a state-owned enterprise,
作为一个国企的干部
He actually does such things?
居然还干这种事啊
To be honest,
说实在的
Doing this could cost you your job.
这样做会丢工作的哈
Of course, uh,
当然来讲的话呃
Each person who filed the lawsuit had different demands.
每个这个起诉他的人这个诉求不一样
I just think that an apology from the other side would be enough.
我就是无非就是觉得对方只要道了歉了
That’s all I need.
其实就行了
They can’t afford to pay compensation.
赔不起钱
But I’m still open to discussion.
其实我都是还是两说
However, since the court has made its decision,
但是法院既然这么判了
we should firmly follow it.
咱们就坚决这么执行
It’s a good outcome.
挺好的啊
He got what he deserved.
他也是罪有应得啊
Whoever is at fault, it’s not good.
说谁不好
Na Fei called me
那非非招我
What did he call me for?
你说招我干什么
Am I the one you're really talking about?
我是不是你要说实在的
If you're willing
你要愿意
Many people are unwilling to go to court
很多人为什么不愿意对簿公堂呢
It's hard to explain this thing
就是这个东西就是怎么说呢
As they say, family scandals should not be made public
所谓的家丑不可外扬
But it doesn't matter to someone like Brother Rong
但是荣哥这样的人其实无所谓
Because as an internet celebrity
因为作为一个网红啊
There's no such thing as personal privacy You need to say If you're going to put it bluntly Then let's talk about that specific incident Is there any event where this didn't happen? He just sticks to the facts and the evidence Right? You can't just make accusations without proof
就是没有什么所谓的个人隐私之类的 你要说 那你要既然撕破脸说的话 那咱们就151十说哪件事 有哪件事没有这东西 他就是讲事实 讲证据的 对不对 不能说你空口就说我
and claim I did this or that
我就怎么怎么样
and then expect me to accept it
然后我就认了
This kind of baseless attack
像这种无端这种攻击呢
is just idle entertainment tabloid-style provocation
闲着没事就搞这种娱乐小报式的攻击呢
which is fundamentally illegal
这东西来讲本身来讲就是法律所不允许的啊
But as I always say
还是那句话啊
know the law and abide by it
知法守法
don’t break the law
不要犯法
promote the law
要宣传法啊
don’t go out of your way to provoke
不要没事去这个招惹
don’t trample on the red lines of society
去踩踩踏这个社会的这个这个红线
We all know about this Weibo platform
咱们也知道这微博这个平台啊
To be honest, it harbors a lot of filth and corruption.
说实在的藏污纳垢非常厉害
Often, they do things that are highly unpopular.
经常是搞一些啊不得人心的事情啊
Then, they incite cyber-bullying,
然后以为煽动网络暴力
thinking no one will hold them accountable.
就没有人会要去追究他的责任啊
They insult others,
侮辱他人
and no one will pursue their responsibility,
就不会有人去追究他这个
or the legal consequences that follow.
后边的这个法律责任啊
Society really needs a few people who are willing to stand up and fight for what's right.
这个东西其实这社会就是缺几个较真的人啊
That's how it is.
就是这样
If you're going to stand up for what's right,
你既然较真的话
Well, of course, speaking of that
就那什么当然来讲的话
We still stand by our statement
咱还是那句话
It's about having professionals handle professional matters
就是专业的人办专业的事啊
No matter what, as an ordinary person You can't possibly have the expertise of law enforcement We're talking about lawyers here And various defense attorneys
你再怎么样作为一个普通的一个人来讲 你不可能有就是公检法啊 咱们说这个这个还有咱们这律师啊 辩护人的这个各种各样的
Their professional skills
这个人家的专业的水平
You definitely lack the professional experience
你肯定是专业水平经验
And the scope of knowledge
还有你这知识的适用范围啊
When it comes to the finer details
一些细节的东西来讲
the professionals definitely have the upper hand
肯定还是人家更专业一点
so I suggest that when you encounter such situations
所以我建议大家呢就是遇到这种事
either you let it go
要么你就忍了
but if you can't swallow your pride
要是你心里不服的话
you should consult a lawyer
就是找律师啊
it's all about letting the experts handle their area of expertise
就这个东西就是专业的人办专业的事
you can't just walk into a hospital
你不能说你上医院啊
and expect them to give you a few computers
医院给你几台电脑
and then use Baidu Deep SG1 to figure out how to treat the illness
你拿上百度deep sg1看这病该怎么治
Then you went for the tests.
然后您就化验去了
You can't just leave it at that, right?
你总不能是这样是吧
Are you saying you went to the hospital to find a lawyer?
你说是上医院找的是律师吗
Didn't you say you were seeing a doctor?
不说找的是医生嘛
Isn't that right?
对不对
That's why it's important to have professionals handle professional matters.
所以这就是专业人办专业的事
The second thing is this...
第二件事就是这个呃
Ever since Brother Rong got his car...
荣哥自打买车了以后啊
It's been one trouble after another.
就是麻烦不断啊
I was thinking about...
我本来是想那个呃
I plan to buy a car before May 30th next year.
明年就是5月30八号之前买车
I'll only keep it for a year.
我就买一年嘛
But I'm worried it might be too rushed at the last minute.
但是呢我这个这个怕到时候临时来不及
If I push it to the limit, and buy the car next May, what if it's too late? The quota will expire. So, I finally decided, maybe I'll buy it during the Spring Festival. In the end, I bought a motorcycle a couple of days ago. I thought buying a motorcycle would be smooth
我要是卡一个极限点 明年5月再买车 万一来不及呢 这指标都作废了啊 所以我最后还是决定啊 要不春节买吧 最后呢前两天买了摩托以后 觉得买摩托很顺
so I ended up getting a car instead
所以就干脆就把汽车买了
I bought a Geely Panda Knight
买了一个吉利的熊猫骑士
and it was on the Guazi Used Cars platform
然后是在这个瓜子二手车那个呃
which you can buy from directly on their website
直卖网上能买的
I originally planned to check out the Zhuanzhuan platform
本来是想去转转平台
but there were fewer listings for the same model on Zhuanzhuan
但转转平台上这同一款车的那个数量少
and the quality wasn't great either
而且那个太次了啊
the whole process on Guazi was pretty enjoyable
瓜子整个这个流程还是挺爽的
they didn't pay me for this endorsement
没有给我广告费
But the entire process, with each person responsible for their part, is
但是他整个这个流程每个人专人对接什么的
pretty quick.
还是比较快的
They handed over the car yesterday.
昨天就把车给呃那个交付了啊
And I’ll be transferring the ownership next week.
然后这个下周去过户啊
To get the Beijing license plate.
过那个户上京牌啊
Well, how to put it,
呃怎么说呢
the car seems quite affordable to me.
给我的感觉就是车是挺便宜的啊
It’s a great deal.
挺划算的
But parking in Beijing is such a hassle.
但是北京停车太难了啊
I definitely need to get the official plates.
我肯定要上了正式牌
Once the official plates are on
然后上了正式牌以后
we need to wait another two weeks on our street before
在我们这街道这边再等个两个礼拜才能在呃
parking near our neighborhood, which is between the second and third ring roads we still can't enter the neighborhood the parking queue for the neighborhood extends to 2023 it hasn't reached 2024 yet I started in 2025 so we need to have an official registration
就是二环外三环里的这个我们这小区附近停车 还不能进小区 小区的这个停车的这个排到23年了啊 还没到24年呢 25年我刚开始 所以来讲的话就得有正式的行驶证啊
not the previous owner's out-of-town license plates
不是上一任车主的那个外地牌照啊
but a Beijing license plate
是北京的牌照
But the official registration can't be a temporary plate.
但是正式行驶证不能是临牌啊
And then there's my property deed.
然后还有我的房本啊
What a mess.
什么乱乱七八糟的
Then you need to register with the community committee to park on the street.
然后在居委会备案停街边
And register with the property management to park in the neighborhood.
然后物业备案停小区
The neighborhood has a waiting list too.
小区又得排队
There's a queue in the neighborhood.
小区排队呢
Either the car owner is dead,
要不就是这车主死了
or the owner has sold the property.
要不就是这个这个这个这个车主把房卖了啊
The new homeowner would have to join the queue again.
新任房主重新排队啊
Anyway, it's pretty bleak.
反正总之就很很渺茫
It's just the first year of junior high school.
初一进一嘛
That's how it is.
就是这样
So parking in old neighborhoods in Beijing is quite difficult.
所以北京的老小区停车是很难的
Many people regret not buying a parking space back then.
很多人说后悔当初没买车位
But now, if you look at houses outside the Fifth Ring Road,
但是现在其实你看五环以外的房子
There are many places where you can park anywhere outside the Fifth Ring Road in Beijing.
北京五环以外的房子很多地方都是随便停
I found one in Shunyi recently,
我现在就找了顺义那边的一个
A neighborhood of one of my followers,
我的粉丝的一个小区
So I think having followers is really beneficial.
所以我觉得还是有粉丝是非常有好处的啊
It was my followers who told me
就是我的粉丝告诉我说
that their residential area doesn’t check or charge for parking fees but for the underground garage you can’t get in but you can park anywhere on the ground and indeed, when I went there, you could park anywhere on the ground so after I got my driver’s license yesterday having not touched a car for 5 years all the driving experience I’ve had is from playing GTA
他们家那小区不查也不收停车费 就地下车库的话 你进不去 但是地上随便停 我一去了以后的确是地上随便停 所以我昨天拿了驾照以后 5年没碰车 天天玩GTA的给我的驾驶经验
I then drove straight from the inspection station to that neighborhood
然后从车的检测场直接开到那个小区了啊
Then next week, I still have to drive another 28 kilometers.
然后下星期还得开两个28km
And then go to handle the transfer procedures.
然后去这个办那过户的事啊
It’s still okay.
还还可以啊
My Beijing entry permit is still valid for seven days next week.
我下星期进京证还在七天有效期之内啊
For those who don’t know what an entry permit is,
就是大家有什么不知道什么叫进竞争证
It’s when you enter Beijing,
就是进北京的时候
You can apply for it 12 times a year,
一年可以办12次
Each time for seven days, totaling 96 days a year.
一次七天加满是96天啊
This allows out-of-town plates to be driven in Beijing,
这就是外地牌照可以在北京开
But they can’t enter the Second Ring Road.
但是不能进二环啊
You can't enter the Second Ring Road.
不能进二环啊
Pretty interesting, huh?
挺有意思的哈
Parking is quite expensive all over Beijing.
北京四处停车都很贵
Like the parking spot in front of my house,
你像我家门口的停车的
most of them charge ten yuan per hour.
大部分都是十块钱一小时啊
There are two or three parking lots that charge ten yuan per hour.
有两个三个停车场都是十块钱一小时啊
There are also cheaper ones at eight yuan per hour.
也有便宜的八块钱一小时的
But if you park for a day, it’s 240 yuan.
但是你要停一天240啊
Even 196 yuan for a day is pretty steep.
停一天196也非常贵了
So parking for a day would be enough for a night in a hotel.
所以我停一天都够住一天酒店的了
Is it?
是不是
I originally thought that in our community, parking on the street was not allowed. Later, our community informed us, that residents of our community can park on both sides of Xueyuan South Road and North Road, starting from the fourth Dao Kou on the left, to the Normal University on the right, along this approximately 34-kilometer-long road,
后来我本来我本来以为我们小区 街边是不能停的 后来我们小区告诉我们 就是我们小区的居民可以在学院南路南侧北侧 就是左起四道口 右起师大 就这个大概34km长的这公路上
parking is permitted on both sides.
两侧都可以停车啊
That would be much more convenient.
那就方便多了
I can wait until others leave for work during the day
我可以等别人白天出去上班的时候
then I quietly stop
我悄悄的停下来
but it's just that I have to walk a bit further from home
但是就是离家走的就比较远啊
not as convenient as parking right outside my door
就不像说是家门口的那个停车那么方便
but parking at the doorstep can be quite troublesome too
但家门口停车也很麻烦
it gets really packed
停的非常满
especially in the morning when everyone is leaving or coming in
不说就是说早上起来大家一出来的进来的
with just one entrance and exit, reversing is often necessary
他就一个出入口就经常得倒车呀
and bumping into each other can be quite a hassle
得互相蹭就比较麻烦
that's why I bought this Panda Knight with a 210km range
所以我买的这熊猫骑士呢续航210km
But it has fast charging.
但是它有快充
And parking is incredibly convenient.
然后他停车是非常的方便
It's more than enough for one person.
一个人用是足够了啊
So, this is Cyborg Grandpa's car buying experience.
所以这就是赛博义父的这个买车的这个经历
The parking experience can be quite complicated.
停车的经历非常复杂
But I got this car for 33,600 yuan.
但是这个车呢我3万3600到手的啊
This is how it works in Beijing.
北京的是这样
There are discounts for buying new cars in Beijing.
北京他买新车是有折扣
Old cars can also be traded in for value.
旧车也可以折价
That means, with the national subsidy and the trade-in value of the old car, I have over 30,000 yuan. For example, I might buy another car next year. Like a BYD model. Or a Tesla model. The 30,000 yuan will be refunded to me.
也就是说加上国补加上旧车折价的话 我得3万多块钱 比如说我明年再买一辆车 比如我买一个比亚迪的什么车 买一个特斯拉什么车 这3万块钱是会还给我的
That is, I traded in my old car.
也就是说我把旧车折了
And with the national subsidy,
再加上国补的话
it’s roughly 30,000 yuan.
大概3万块钱
It’s like I didn’t spend a penny,
等于我一分钱没花
to buy this car.
买了这车啊
Then the aunt compensated me with 10,000 yuan.
然后是大妈赔我1万块钱
I used the 10,000 yuan to buy a motorcycle.
我1万块钱买摩托车
So it was like the aunt bought it for me.
等于是大妈给买的
Then, this bike cost 30,000 yuan in total.
然后这车呢来讲花了3万块钱
When I buy a new car,
等买了新车的时候
I can get the 30,000 yuan back.
这3万块钱还能回来
So essentially, I got two vehicles for free.
所以来讲等于就是白嫖了两辆车
Pretty good.
挺好的
Saving money to the max.
省钱省到极致啊
Lastly, I want to mention something that concerns everyone.
然后最后说一件事跟大家都有关的啊
So everyone knows about my course, right?
就是呃大家知道我的那个课程吧
Yeah, I'm still working hard on it, even with all the other stuff going on.
啊我最近还在跟我这25线真格呢
I promise I will definitely finish updating it this month.
啊这个这个月一定会给大家更完的
Well, I have the right to sell courses on this platform.
呃这个我因为在平台上来讲是有卖课的权利的
Many of my followers,
就是我的很多粉丝
for example, are chess masters or Pilates instructors,
他们比如说是围棋高手或普拉提的教练啊
or coaches for math competitions,
还有什么数学的竞赛的教练
or art teachers,
还有什么教画画的
or music instructors,
教音乐的
or fine arts educators.
教美术的
all sorts of talented people if you want to collaborate with me like posting your courses on my channel we can actually work together when it comes to the courses I post I have a company contract with Bilibili
就各种各样的人人才啊 如果你们想跟我合作 比如说在我的频道发布你们的课的话 其实咱们是可以合作的 因为我发的课来讲的话 因为我跟B站签的是公司约
speaking of which
来讲的话
it’s actually a collaboration with the company
其实是来讲的话是公司的合作
it’s not like I, Rong Zhen, am the one giving all the lectures
不是说一切都是我荣振本人来讲这个课
for example, if you have a great course
比如说你有什么很好的课
I think people will like it
你觉得大家会喜欢
People will be willing to pay for it
大家会掏钱买
Then you teach me
然后呢你教给我
Basically, you need to record something over 30 minutes long
大概呢你就是要录这个总长30分钟以上
And it should be at level five or above
然后五级以上啊
Ideally, I think it’s best to record between ten to twenty episodes
基本上来讲我觉得最好是录个十集到20集啊
The total length should be a few hours
总长度最好是几个小时
Four to six hours would be ideal
4~6个小时为宜
If you have something in this area
如果你有这方面的东西来讲
Find someone to help you record
找一个人帮你录
Or you can take a selfie
或者你自己自拍
Record yourself
自己在那录
After you're done recording
录完了以后呢
You can start with one episode
你可以先录一集
Then find a way to contact me
然后呢找个跟我的联系方式啊
Send it to me first
先发给我
Let me take a look
让我看一下
Then I'll give you some guidance
然后我给你指导一下
Our course revenue is split fifty-fifty
然后呢咱们的麦子所有的课呢是五五分成啊
You can, for example, use this tool
你就可以比如说啊用这个东西
For instance, if you do a great job
比如说你弄得非常好的话
course by course
一门课一门课的话
you can typically earn a few thousand dollars without any issue
通常来讲的话挣个几万块钱是没有问题的啊
so the income from this is quite substantial on top of your regular activities for example, if you are a college student now you have just finished your postgraduate entrance exam you got accepted into a postgraduate program but you are interested in political science for the postgraduate entrance exam or the English for the postgraduate entrance exam I have a lot of insights when it comes to preparing for the postgraduate math exam. Or are you currently taking the French exam?
所以来讲的话这个收入还是非常可观的 是在你业余之外 比如说你现在是大学生 你刚刚考完了考研究生 你考上研究生了 但是你对考研政治 考研英语 考研数学特别有心得啊 或者说你现在在考法语啊
You're taking the TCF French exam.
你考法语TCF
You have insights in this area.
你有这方面的心得啊
We can summarize and turn it into a video course.
都可以总结成把它弄弄成视频课
Then collaborate with me.
然后跟我合作
Work together with me.
跟我合作
We'll release it.
咱们发布
And we split all the costs down the middle.
然后所有的这个费用呢咱们一人一半啊
That's my actual income after all is said and done.
这个就是我到手的实际的收益来讲
We can each post half of it.
咱们可以一人一半这么发布啊
This way is better.
这样来讲比较好
And the course is not primarily for Follower courses.
而且课程它主要来讲它不是面对粉丝课程
He uses apartment traffic.
他用的是公寓流量
That means people who might not know me at all.
也就是说可能完全不认识我的人
Then they would come across my content through this.
然后呢他会通过这个东西来刷到我
Of course, if you start a new account, it’s different.
当然来讲你起一个新号来讲的话
It definitely won’t match my large account.
肯定不如我这种大号
The traffic flows more smoothly with this approach.
这个流量比较怎么说通畅啊
Usually, there won’t be any review or blocking issues.
通常也不会有什么审核拦截之类的
So, if you're looking for me,
所以来讲的话你们找我的话
working with me is a very suitable way,
跟我合作是一个非常合适的一种方式啊
so I've brought this lesson to share with everyone.
这样来讲的话就把这课带上给大家了
this is also for you,
这也是你啊
how to put it,
怎么说呢
to hone personal skills,
磨练个人技能啊
to summarize and conclude,
进行归纳总结
and it's also a good way to earn extra income. now, online knowledge payment is a trend, various skills Actually, everyone is willing to spend money on these things. As for the pricing,
再进行这个赚取外快的一种比较好的方式啊 现在是互联网知识付费是一个趋势啊 各种各样的技能 其实大家都是愿意为这些东西花钱的 呃至于定价来讲
I'll set it for you.
我会帮你定
And when it comes to specifics,
然后在具体的东西来讲
I hope you can contact me via WeChat at that time.
我希望你们到时候就跟我的微信联系
You can add it to my signature.
就可以可以在我的签名档里边加
I
我
can also say,
也可以说啊
feel free to leave a message for me,
这个给我发留言
or send a message to my group admins.
或者给我的几个群管理员发留言
Don't @ me
不要艾特我啊
Tag the group admin
艾特群管理员
if they're willing to work with me
让他们愿意跟我合作的话
after watching this episode
看过这期节目以后
everyone is welcome to collaborate with me
大家欢迎跟我合作啊
these are the three major events in my recent life
这就是我近期发生的三件大事
I originally planned to stretch it into three episodes
本来想水成三期的
but then I thought it would be better to save everyone's time
后来想尽量节约大家时间
so here it is, all in one episode
这就是一期发布完哈啊
wish everyone a pleasant weekend
祝大家这个周末愉快